Subtitles by explosiveskull Colored by novabros
LORRAINE : I had a vision in Amityville .
I had a premonition of your death .
( SCREAMS )
We have both seen the same inhuman spirit .
Mom , who 's that ?
LORRAINE : The demon in your painting is real .
( WIND HOWLING )
( METAL CREAKING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Are you certain we 're making the right decision ?
We have no other choice .
( SISTER VICTORIA BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SISTER JESSICA SIGHS )
Will the relic truly save us ?
Have faith , Sister .
( CRYING ) Our Father , who art in heaven ,
hallowed be thy name .
Thy kingdom come ,
thy will be done on Earth as it is in heaven .
Give us this day our daily bread .
And forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those who trespass against us .
( CHAINS RATTLING ) ( SISTER JESSICA SCREAMS )
( WHIMPERING LOUDLY )
( CONTINUES WHIMPERING )
SISTER JESSICA : ( PANTING ) Take it !
This evil needs a vessel to escape .
It will come after you next .
Don 't let it have you .
You know what you must do . I can 't .
Then not even God can save ... ( BOTH SCREAMING )
( ROARING )
( SISTER VICTORIA YELPING )
( PANTING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SISTER VICTORIA CRYING )
( DOOR OPENING ) ( GASPS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( CONTINUES BREATHING HEAVILY )
Forgive me , Father ,
for the sin I 'm about to commit .
( CRYING )
( GASPS )
( CONTINUES CRYING )
Forgive me , Lord .
( CHAIN RATTLING )
( CREAKING )
( MAN SINGING IN FRENCH )
( GRUNTING )
( CONTINUES SINGING IN FRENCH )
( CROWS CAWING ) ( PANTING )
( CAWING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( IN ENGLISH ) Oh , God .
( CROWS SQUAWKING )
( DOOR OPENS ) ( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
BISHOP PASQUALE : Father Burke ?
Bishop .
BISHOP PASQUALE : So the last time you were here
was what night ?
Six , seven years ago ?
FATHER BURKE : After my time as a chaplain
ended in the war , yes .
Well , we appreciate you coming again
under such short notice .
( DOOR OPENS )
Father Burke .
Sit .
We have received news
that a nun has taken her own life
at an abbey in the mountains of Romania .
Suicide is a terrible , terrible sin .
But it doesn 't strike me
as strong enough reason for a reunion .
But the news of it would not bolster
our argument to keep
with the faith and the Church .
You 're not telling me something .
Why do you say that ?
Because we 're in the Vatican .
Let me put it this way , Father .
In this , albeit , rare instance ,
we do not believe
we 're the ones with the secret .
BISHOP PASQUALE : Those are your travel documents
and contact information
on the man who discovered the nun .
He lives near the abbey
in a small village called Biertan .
You will want to talk to him first .
Also in the file is the name of a postulant who can help
assist you in your inquiries
since it is a cloistered convent
and your access will be limited .
She 's also familiar with the territory .
SISTER IRENE : I have survived many terrifying encounters .
But nothing could have ever prepared me for this .
My only hope now was that the beast could not smell me .
But then , the wind changed and ...
( ROARS ) (
STUDENTS GASP )
( SCREAMS ) ( STUDENTS LAUGHING )
Run for your lives !
Mother Superior says that dinosaurs
were never really alive .
God just put their bones here to test our faith .
That seems like a pretty dirty trick , don 't you think ?
GIRL : But they 're not in the Bible .
SISTER IRENE : Well , do you believe in penguins and koala bears ?
ALL : Yes .
They aren 't in the Bible either .
The Bible is God 's love letter to us ,
but it doesn 't mean that He doesn 't want us to ask questions
about the wonders of His creation .
But Mother Superior says ... ( GASPS )
Wait a minute . You 've got a little something on your nose .
There . ( STUDENTS LAUGH )
Ahem .
( STUDENTS GASP )
STUDENTS : Ooh !
SISTER IRENE : The Vatican ? I 'm as surprised as you .
I haven 't even taken my vows yet .
Oh , he 's aware of that .
He 's waiting for you in the garden .
And change into your habit .
This is an official visit .
FATHER BURKE : It shouldn 't take more than a few days , at most .
You were recommended for the journey
because of your familiarity with the territory .
" The territory " ?
Yes . Romania .
I 'd never been in that part of the world .
Really ?
There must 've been some mistake .
I apologize if you coming here was a waste of your time .
Oh , no , no . No apology necessary .
Every decision the Vatican makes is with purpose .
I 'm sure they had their reasons for selecting you .
( GASPING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
What is it ?
Mr. Theriault ?
Hi .
Jealous husband or angry father ?
I 'm sorry , what ?
Well , usually it 's one of the two
when an older man and a young , beautiful ,
not-so-innocent girl show up on my doorstep
at this hour of the morning .
I beg your pardon , Mr. Theriault ,
but you and I have never met .
Oh .
Oh . Then perhaps it 's time we did .
Call me Frenchie .
Everyone does .
Mr. Theriault , we are here
because of the nun you found at the abbey .
How 'd you ...
Are you priest ?
And she is a nun .
Oh . (
CHUCKLING )
Forgive me for my impure thoughts , Sister .
I had no idea .
Never seen a nun out of her vestments .
Not that I 'm opposed to it .
Excuse me .
Monsieur Theriault ,
the abbey .
Is it far ?
In matter of distance , no , but it takes time to get to .
If I may ask , why were you there ?
I was delivering the quarterly supplies .
Apparently , the abbey has had some kind of arrangement
with the village for centuries .
FATHER BURKE : Do you think you could take us there sometime soon ?
FRENCHIE : I don 't think so , Father .
Is there someone else in the village , then ?
Everyone in this village
pretend like the abbey doesn 't exist .
Even talking about it might get you in trouble .
It 's settled , then . You will take us .
With all due respect , Father , I ...
Please , Frenchie .
( BOTH SPEAKING ROMANIAN )
You took a plane from Rome , a bus from Bucharest .
Now , my friends , you 're in the Dark Ages .
In the backwoods of Romania . ( ENGINE STALLS )
( ENGINE STARTS )
Now , you travel by horse .
Where are your things ? ( LAUGHING )
( WHISTLES )
( CONTINUES LAUGHING )
FATHER BURKE : " The postman 's charge . "
Ten letters with an " L. "
Deliveries .
You have a knack for this , Sister .
SISTER IRENE : What brings a Frenchman
to the countryside of Romania ?
Actually , I 'm French-Canadian , but don 't tell anyone .
Doesn 't sound as romantic .
I came here looking for gold
but when I met the people here ,
I just knew this was the place I was meant to be .
Wanted to help them . Any way I could .
That 's very noble of you .
I know .
Tell me , Sister , how long have you been a nun ?
I 'm not a nun yet . I 'm still just a novitiate .
You still haven 't taken your temporary vows ?
" Temporary " ?
I didn 't think there was anything temporary
about being a nun .
Temporary vows would help prepare me
for a life of total consecration .
" Would , " Sister ? Or " will " ?
Whoa .
What happened ?
Everything all right ? ( HORSE WHINNIES )
FRENCHIE : We walk the rest of the way .
The horse won 't go any further .
( SISTER IRENE GRUNTS )
Maybe you should get a new horse .
Well , it 's not the horse , Father .
It 's what lies ahead . He 's scared .
The locals say it 's a cursed place
and the horse agrees .
SISTER IRENE : If I may ask , Father ,
why is it the Church sends you on such tasks ?
The Church reaches out to me when it needs an investigation
into unusual phenomenon associated with Catholicism .
Unofficially , they call it " miracle hunting . "
I thought we were here because of a suicide .
We are , but it 's only part of our investigation .
I also have orders from the Vatican to determine
if the grounds are still ... holy .
FRENCHIE : Well , I can give you my opinion
on that now , Father .
A result of the war ?
Bombing raids , yes .
I 've heard stories of how the ground shook for days after them .
I 've tried to find more information on the castle itself ,
but there 's no record of it in the village .
And the locals only spit when it 's mentioned .
" Spit " ? Yeah , to ward off evil .
It 's an old and silly superstition .
And if you ask me ,
these crosses that surround the abbey
they keep the evil in , not out .
Did you try to contact someone inside when you found the nun ?
FRENCHIE : I did . No one responded .
But then again ,
in the two years I 've been delivering supplies ,
she was the first one I 'd seen .
FATHER BURKE : Frenchie , when you found the nun , what did you do ?
FRENCHIE : I moved it to protect the body from the elements .
FATHER BURKE : Where did you move it to , son ?
The icehouse .
It 's where I leave my deliveries .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
When I found the sister , I thought
maybe moving her in here would help preserve her .
Uh ...
( MUMBLES )
( SIGHS )
( SPEAKS FRENCH )
( FRENCHIE SIGHS )
I should tell you one more thing , Father .
What ?
That 's not how I left her .
What do you mean ?
She was laying down when I left her here .
Not like that , sitting up .
FATHER BURKE : There have been cases
of bodies twitching or sitting up ,
not long after death .
Yeah , but , Father , who knows
how long she was dead when I found her ?
You 're not helping .
Sorry .
SISTER IRENE : Father , what is it ?
It seems to be a key of some kind .
( DOOR RATTLING )
That 's the door the nuns would enter from
to retrieve the supplies .
So they wouldn 't have to leave the castle .
We should give her a proper burial .
( PRAYING IN LATIN )
( BELL RINGING )
( IN ENGLISH ) It was common practice
during the plague .
When people feared to be buried alive .
If you were unfortunate enough for it to happen ,
you could ring the bell to let those above ground know
they have made a mistake .
I think being here is a mistake .
( RINGING )
FRENCHIE : That 's where I found her .
How is that possible ? It 's been weeks .
I told you . This place is ...
What 's the opposite of a miracle , Father ?
( DOOR CLOSES )
( SISTER IRENE GASPS )
( SHUDDERING )
Hello ?
Please excuse us for our unannounced arrival .
THE ABBESS : What is it you want ?
I 'm Father Anthony Burke .
This is Sister Irene .
Are you the Reverend Mother ?
THE ABBESS : I am .
You haven 't taken your vows yet .
Uh ...
(
STAMMERS ) No .
Please ... Why are you here , Father ?
We come on behalf of Rome ,
to inquire about the recent death in your convent .
THE ABBESS : " Recent death " ?
One of your nuns .
I found her outside . Hanged from the neck .
( THE ABBESS SPEAKING FRENCH )
( IN ENGLISH ) Would you allow us a moment , please ?
THE ABBESS : You should leave with him .
Are you saying you weren 't aware
of the recent passing of the nun ?
Rome is concerned about the safety
and well-being of your cloister .
I 'd like to speak with the sisters
so I can offer my assurances to the Church .
THE ABBESS : I can offer the assurance you seek .
I 'm afraid that won 't suffice .
They will just send more , and , uh ,
perhaps less diplomatic , church officials .
THE ABBESS : Yes , Father .
However , the gate will be closing shortly
as we are about to take our vespers .
Followed by the Great Silence which ends midmorning .
Come back tomorrow
and you will find the answers you seek .
There is lodging in the convent .
You may stay there .
Thank you .
FRENCHIE : Why could you not talk to the sisters now ?
Why must it wait till morning ?
The sisters take a vow of silence
from sunset to sunrise
that must be respected .
You should begin heading back yourself .
I imagine you don 't want to be caught on those roads when night falls .
Better the roads than here , Father .
We 'll be fine , son . Come back in a few days .
That should give us enough time to get what we need .
Yes , Father .
( SINGING IN FRENCH )
( GASPS )
Hello ?
( LEAVES RUSTLING )
Hey .
Hey !
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( DISTANT ANIMAL SOUNDS ) ( CONTINUES BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GRUNTING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GRUNTS ) ( SNARLS )
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING ) ( GROWLING )
( YELPING )
I 'll take ( GRUNTS ) that .
( PANTING )
Okay .
All right .
( JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING )
SISTER IRENE : Father ? Hmm ?
You mentioned " miracle hunting " before .
Is that ...
Is that a role you sought out ?
No .
God , no .
(
CHUCKLES ) I 'm a part of a small select few
the Church relies on to
look into their more
unusual matters .
So , you know Bishop Forne ?
How do you ...
Because he helped me when I was younger .
I had a series of visions when I was a girl .
My father believed I was mentally unstable .
Or worse , a liar .
But word of my visions reached the Church .
Cardinal Conroy , specifically .
And he sent Bishop Forne to meet with me .
What were your visions ?
( SIGHS ) There were many .
Never the same one repeated .
But after each one ended ,
the same thought would be stuck in my head .
Which was ... what ?
" Mary points the way . "
( FATHER BURKE SIGHS )
What is it , Father ?
I was thinking of a similar incident
I encountered in France . During the war .
I was stationed there . Near Lyon .
I was told to investigate a boy with visions .
( DANIEL BREATHING HEAVILY )
But , unlike your case ,
after what I believe was careful evaluation ...
( SNIFFS )
I made the judgment he was possessed ,
and proceeded to act accordingly
within the laws of the Church .
My God . Daniel ...
What have they done to you ?
( DANIEL SNARLING )
Was it a success ?
The Church thought so .
They believed the evil was cast out .
But not you .
( SNARLING CONTINUES )
Most Glorious Prince
of the Heavenly Armies , Saint Michael , the archangel ...
(
OBJECTS
CLATTERING )
( CRYING ) Help me , Father !
Come to the assistance of Daniel ,
whom God has made in His likeness !
( SCREAMS ) Behold the Cross of the Lord !
Why won 't you help me ?
Ye hostile forces !
( SCREAMING )
Daniel sustained severe injuries
during the exorcism .
Ones from which he could not recover .
Daniel , I 'm so sorry .
He died days later .
I often wonder if I was too eager
with my determination .
That is a puzzle .
( STATIC )
( JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUSIC STOPS )
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING ) ( OBJECTS CLATTERING )
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING )
DANIEL : (
WHISPERS ) Father .
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING )
( RUSTLING )
( THUNDER CRASHING )
( TWIG SNAPS )
( RUSTLING )
DANIEL : (
WHISPERS ) Father .
Daniel ?
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( DANIEL GAGGING )
( YELPS )
Wait ! No ! Help ! ( POUNDING ON DOOR )
Help ! No !
( BELL RINGING )
( WIND HOWLING )
( CHURCH BELL TOLLING )
Help !
Somebody .
( EERIE CHANTING )
( EERIE CHANTING CONTINUES )
( GASPS )
( SHUDDERS )
( GROWLING )
( YELPS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY ) ( CROSS CREAKING )
( GASPING )
( GRUNTING ) ( POUNDING ON DOOR )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( RINGING )
Help ! Sister Irene ! Help !
( BELL CONTINUES RINGING )
Father ! Father ?
( PANTING )
Father ?
( CONTINUES PANTING )
( CONTINUES RINGING )
( GASPS )
( BELLS RINGING )
( RINGING INTENSIFIES )
Help !
Help me !
( GASPS )
( SINGLE BELL RINGING )
Father ? ( MUFFLED ) Sister ?
Sister Irene ! Father , I can hear you !
(
POUNDING ON DOOR ) I 'm right here !
( PANTING ) Oh , thank God . Thank you .
( GRUNTING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( INAUDIBLE )
( SCRATCHING )
( SISTER IRENE GRUNTING )
( SCRATCHING CONTINUES )
( GRUNTING )
( THUDS )
( SHOVEL THUDDING )
( SIGHS )
( YELPING )
Hurry !
( CONTINUES YELPING )
( GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
( GRUNTS LOUDLY ) Wait ! Wait !
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( FATHER BURKE GRUNTING )
( GASPING )
( PANTING ) ( COUGHING )
Thank you . Thank you , Sister .
( GRUNTING )
How did you get in there ? The ground was covered .
There is a powerful evil presence in this place .
Maybe those books will help shine a light on our answer .
SISTER IRENE : There 's more of it .
How is that possible ?
Another puzzle . ( CHURCH BELL TOLLING )
Abbess ?
As requested ,
we are here to speak with the nuns .
It seems like that 's as much as an invitation as we 'll get .
I 'll go find the Abbess .
Take this .
See what you can find out about it .
It was obviously important to the deceased .
Sister . Be careful , please .
I will , Father .
( CHURCH BELL TOLLING ) ( THUNDER RUMBLING )
Hello ?
Wait !
( SISTER RUTH PRAYING IN LATIN )
Sister ?
( SISTER RUTH CONTINUES IN LATIN )
SISTER OANA : ( IN ENGLISH ) Sister !
We mustn 't stop praying , even for a second .
This convent has had
perpetual adoration for centuries .
The sisters pray in shifts to maintain a constant vigil .
I am so sorry to have disturbed her .
Sister Ruth has withstood
more than just someone sneaking up behind her .
I 'm Sister Oana . We were told you were coming .
Please , follow me .
( SISTER RUTH CONTINUES IN LATIN )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
What ?
Another round .
I told Luca it was on the house .
FRENCHIE : Why did she cover the mirror ?
It 's tradition here when someone dies .
You cover the mirror ,
so the deceased doesn 't see their reflection
and become a ghost .
Someone died ?
You didn 't hear ? Luca 's daughter committed suicide .
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
I can 't believe it . She was just a kid .
Twelve years old . Hanged herself in his barn .
Hanged herself ? Why ?
Why did Addi Constantine 's crop turn to dust ?
Why was little Stefan struck blind ?
It is that place . The abbey .
Whatever evil is up there , it 's leaking out ,
poisoning us .
( SPITS )
And that , uh , couple you took up there yesterday .
Who were they ? Priest and a nun .
Are they still up there ?
Yeah . Pick them up tomorrow .
You recently discovered a body up there , didn 't you ?
Yeah , Grigore , yeah .
Well , I believe you 're about to discover two more .
FATHER BURKE : And out of the ground
formed every beast of the field
and every bird of the sky .
And whatever the man called the demon creature ,
that was its name .
Valak .
The Defiler .
The Profane .
The Marquis of Snakes .
( RATTLING )
Sister !
Sister Irene !
SISTER OANA : Sister Victoria 's death
was a terrible tragedy for the convent ,
but we still feel her presence .
She was the most devoted out of any of us .
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Excuse me , Sister .
Sister Vic ... ( DOOR LOCK CLANKS )
( DOOR CREAKING )
Forgive us ,
we 're highly protective of our privacy .
Some of the sisters would prefer
I not speak to you at all .
We appreciate your willingness to do so .
Sister Oana ,
can you tell me about the history of this abbey ?
It was built by a duke in the Dark Ages .
The Duke of Saint Carta .
He wrote countless texts on witchcraft and rituals ,
in which to call upon the forces of hell .
Hell used him to open a gateway
so that an unspeakable evil
would walk amongst us .
( RUMBLING )
But the Church stormed the castle .
They sealed the gateway using an ancient relic
containing the blood of Jesus Christ .
The Church claimed the castle for their own
and our perpetual praying began
to secure the abbey and contain the evil .
For centuries it worked and evil was kept at bay
until the bombs of war shook the abbey
and evil found another way to open the gateway .
Sister Oana , last night in the chapel ,
I saw a nun .
She was ... She felt anything but holy .
Do you see her , too ?
I 've seen her stalking the hallways at night .
We all have .
She looks like us , but she 's not one of us .
It 's something unholy .
It takes on different forms to deceive us
and prey on our weaknesses .
It appears as a nun so it can hide among our cloister
until it can corrupt us all .
I fear her presence means the portal has opened again .
It made Sister Victoria commit the ultimate sin .
SISTER ABIGAIL : Sister Oana .
Sister Ruth is nearly finished with her prayers .
It 's time you attend to yours .
SISTER OANA : Yes , Sister .
You haven 't taken your vows yet ?
No .
Then this is not a place for you .
You need to leave now . SISTER OANA : She can 't .
The gates have closed .
You must stay until they open again .
When do they open ?
SISTER OANA : Sunrise . You must stay the night .
Sister Irene .
Good night , Sister .
Sister , wait .
Yes ?
Sister Victoria had this
in her possession when she died .
Do you happen to know what it 's for ?
No .
Now , please , I must go pray .
( LOCK CLICKS )
( FOOTSTEPS RETREATING )
Where are you ?
THE ABBESS : You won 't find another way in , Father .
Abbess ?
THE ABBESS : What is it that concerns you ?
I 'm afraid
there 's something very wrong with this place , Abbess .
THE ABBESS : Like many places in this world ,
the abbey has a long history .
Not all good but we repent .
That nun , I found her
clutching the key in her hands .
What does it open , Abbess ?
THE ABBESS : It 's too late , Father .
Sister Irene is lost .
( BONES CRACK )
Abbess ?
( FATHER BURKE YELPING ) ( CANDLE CLATTERS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( THUNDER CRASHING )
FATHER BURKE : Sister Irene .
SISTER IRENE : Mary points the way .
( ECHOING ) Mary points the way .
Mary points the way .
( SCREAMS )
( GASPS )
( SHUDDERING )
( RUSTLING )
( VOICE PRAYING IN LATIN )
Who are you ? ( BONES CRACKING )
( PRAYER BEADS CLINKING )
( SHIVERING )
God save you . ( GASPS )
( GASPS ) ( KNOCK ON DOOR )
( DOOR UNLOCKS )
( SISTER IRENE BREATHING HEAVILY )
SISTER VICTORIA : Sister , please come .
Sister Oana ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WATER DRIPPING )
( SISTER IRENE BREATHING HEAVILY )
( DOOR UNLOCKS )
( GASPS )
Oh , God .
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WIND HOWLING )
( GRUNTING )
( CONTINUES GRUNTING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SCREAMING )
( GROANS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( SCREAMING )
( PANTING ) ( ROARING )
( CONTINUES SCREAMING )
( MUFFLED SCREAMING )
( MUFFLED WHIMPERING )
(
WHISPERS ) Quiet .
The evil grows stronger .
Get your things and meet me in the chapel , Sister .
Only prayer will get us through the night .
Go . Leave .
Now .
( WHISPERING VOICES )
( SISTER ABIGAIL PRAYING IN LATIN )
SISTER IRENE : Hello ?
( SISTER ABIGAIL CONTINUES PRAYING IN LATIN )
SISTER IRENE : Sister Oana ?
DANIEL : How long have I been dead , Father ?
How long ?
Daniel ?
I 'm sorry .
( SHOUTS ) Why won 't you help me ?
( RUMBLING )
( GASPS )
( GRUNTING ) ( SNARLING )
( SISTER ABIGAIL PRAYING IN LATIN )
SISTER RUTH : We need to pray , now .
And whatever happens , whatever you may see or hear ,
keep your eyes forward and don 't stop praying .
( ALL PRAYING IN LATIN )
( GASPING )
( PRAYING IN LATIN )
( ALL CONTINUE PRAYING ) ( SISTER IRENE PANTING )
( SISTER IRENE PRAYING IN LATIN )
( SCREAMS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( PRAYING IN LATIN )
FRENCHIE : That 's the door the nuns would enter from
to retrieve the supplies .
So they wouldn 't have to leave the castle .
( BELL RINGS )
( BELL RINGING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GROWLING )
No , no .
( FATHER BURKE GRUNTING )
( OBJECTS CLATTER ) ( SNARLING )
( FRENCHIE GRUNTING )
( PANTING )
( EXHALES SHARPLY ) Holy mother of God .
Frenchie !
Thought you could use some help .
( FATHER BURKE BREATHING HEAVILY )
Thank you .
But please , by all means , next time , do use the shotgun .
Well , I 'm saving that for emergencies , Father .
( PRAYING IN LATIN )
( SNIFFLES )
( NUNS GROANING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( GASPS )
( GROANS )
( GROANING )
( POUNDING ON DOOR ) ( NUNS CONTINUE PRAYING )
FATHER BURKE : Sister !
Sister Irene !
( POUNDING CONTINUES )
SISTER IRENE : Father Burke .
( GROANS )
It 's Father Burke . He will help us .
( POUNDING ON DOOR ) FATHER BURKE : Sister !
( LOUD POUNDING ON DOOR )
Sister Irene !
( SISTER IRENE GRUNTING )
SISTER IRENE : Oh , thank God , Father .
Are you all right , Sister ? ( EXHALES SHARPLY )
Frenchie ?
What happened ?
We , we 've been praying , all of us together .
Perpetual adoration ,
it 's the only thing that 's been holding back the evil .
Who 's been praying ?
All of us . The other nuns .
They were here .
They were praying when we were attacked .
The nuns tried to warn me .
Visions .
They felt so real .
There 's no one left .
We have our answer , Father .
As if there was any doubt before ,
this place is no longer holy .
( FATHER BURKE SIGHS )
Oh , Father . Lord Jesus ... ( SNARLS )
( ALL GRUNTING )
FRENCHIE : Father , what do we do ?
( SNARLING )
Get my bag , Sister ! Hand me the cross !
Put some holy water on it . Here , hurry !
Please , Father , hurry !
( CHANTS IN LATIN ) ( SNARLS )
Hold it down ! Cover its face !
( FRENCHIE GRUNTING )
( FATHER BURKE CHANTS IN LATIN )
( IN ENGLISH ) I cast out the demon in you ,
in the name of God the Father Almighty !
And the power of the holy spirit ,
I ask this in the name of our Father , Jesus Christ ,
who is coming to judge both the living and the dead ,
and the world of fire !
( GROANS LOUDLY )
( GASPING )
( GRUNTS )
( ALL PANTING )
That felt like an emergency .
We 're too late .
The evil is free .
No .
For the demon to enter our world ,
it must possess a human soul .
Sister Victoria must have been the last nun in this cloister .
SISTER JESSICA : You know what you must do .
I can 't .
Then not even God can save ... ( SCREAMING )
It wasn 't suicide .
It was a sacrifice ,
so the evil wouldn 't take her soul .
I did not understand a word you just said , but , uh ...
Sounds like your investigation 's complete .
So , let 's get outta here .
We can 't just leave .
Oh , come on . Why the hell not ?
We have to seal the gateway , to contain the evil .
SISTER IRENE : The gateway is in the catacombs .
( FATHER BURKE GRUNTS ) But we can 't close it
without the relic . The blood of Christ .
" Christ . " Jesus Christ ?
Did the sisters tell you where it is ?
The Abbess was found dead
in the tunnel to the catacombs .
( SIGHS )
I think I know where that tunnel is .
Good . Then , that 's where we look first .
But , Father , before we do ,
I 'd like to take my vows .
Are you certain ?
My visions .
I now know they are a miracle of God .
And I am ready to commit my life to Him .
FRENCHIE : Now , that , Sister , is a noble act .
It 's a shame , but ...
FATHER BURKE : By the authority entrusted to me ,
and in the name of the Church ,
I receive the vows you have taken .
I earnestly commend you to God .
That your gift of self , is made one
with the sacrifice of the Eucharist .
And might be brought to perfection .
May the love of God unite you forever and ever .
( PRAYS IN LATIN )
( WATER DRIPPING )
FRENCHIE : Well , there 's nothing here .
SISTER IRENE : There has to be .
They told me this key unlocks a door to the relic .
That could be anywhere in the castle .
It is here . Don 't you see it , Sister ?
What ?
Mary points the way .
( GASPS )
FATHER BURKE : The blood of Christ .
Holy shit .
The holiest .
Only a true bride of Christ can wield something so sacred .
Wait .
What is it ?
Shouldn 't we say a prayer or something , first ?
There 's a time for prayer , and a time for action , son .
Now is the time for action .
Also still feels like a time for prayer as well , Father .
" Finit hic , Deo . " God ends here .
( DOOR OPENS )
SISTER IRENE : We need to search everywhere
to find the gateway .
( METAL CLANGING )
( FRENCHIE BREATHING HEAVILY )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( SNARLING ) ( GASPS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING )
VOICE : (
WHISPERING ) Sister Irene , this way .
( SISTER IRENE GASPS )
Hello ? ( GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
( NUN SNARLING )
Sister Irene !
Sister !
( PANTING )
( SCREAMS )
( SISTER IRENE SCREAMS ) ( GASPS )
Irene !
( GRUNTS )
( WHISPERING VOICES )
( NUNS CHANTING )
( BONES CRACKING ) ( CHANTING STOPS )
( CHANTING CONTINUES )
Lord Jesus , in your Holy Name ,
I bind all evil spirits to this fire !
Protect us from evil with your holy light !
( LANTERN GLASS SHATTERS )
( CHANTING CONTINUES )
( GRUNTS )
( GROANS )
( GASPS )
SISTER IRENE : Frenchie . Help me .
Of course .
( PANTING )
( GASPS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( FRENCHIE PRAYING IN FRENCH )
( SCREECHING ) ( FRENCHIE SCREAMING )
No !
You failed .
Just as you have failed everyone in your life .
( GRUNTING )
Tomorrow , a village will be missing its idiot .
You should 've kept running
when you had the chance , Frenchman .
I am French-Canadian .
( FRENCHIE GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
Run !
( FRENCHIE GROANING )
SISTER IRENE : Frenchie !
( FRENCHIE SCREAMING )
No !
( HISSING )
( SCREAMING )
( CHOKING ) ( SNARLING )
( GASPING )
Sister !
Sister Irene !
( SNARLING ) ( FATHER BURKE GRUNTING )
( SNAKE HISSING )
( CHOKING )
( HISSING )
( GROANING )
( GASPING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( WHIMPERING )
( SISTER IRENE SCREAMING )
( SNARLING )
In the name of the Father , the Son , and the Holy Spirit .
( CHANTING IN LATIN )
( SCREAMING )
( SNARLING )
( GASPS )
( SPITS )
( SCREECHING )
( SCREAMING )
( FRENCHIE GRUNTING )
No , no , no , no , no !
( PANTING )
Come on .
( COUGHING )
Okay .
( GROANS )
FRENCHIE : I hope you don 't mind .
It 's called " the kiss of life . "
It 's just called that way . It 's just , it 's not really ...
Frenchie , what 's your real name ?
Maurice .
Thank you for saving my life , Maurice .
You 're welcome .
We should get going .
SISTER IRENE : Into your hands , O Lord ,
we humbly deliver your servants .
The nuns of Saint Carta .
They served you in this life with strength and faith .
Deliver them now from every evil .
And let them live with you in perfect grace , forever .
Amen .
Thought this ground wasn 't holy anymore .
It is now .
Will you stay on in Biertan ?
FRENCHIE : Oh , I think I 've had my fill of Romania .
My father was a tomato farmer .
Maybe I 'll try that for a while .
Sounds a little boring for a world traveler like you .
( CHUCKLES ) Certainly hope so .
ED : An exorcism can be very dangerous .
Not only for the victim , but for anyone in the room .
Take Maurice Theriault ,
his friends called him Frenchie .
He was a French-Canadian farmer .
Nothing more than a third grade education .
Yet , after he was possessed ...
( SNARLS ) (
CHOKING )
ED : ... spoke some of the best Latin I 'd ever heard .
LORRAINE : And like that , an upside-down cross
started to appear from within his body .
ED : Which brings me to the three stages
of demonic activity .
Infestation , oppression , and possession .
( LORRAINE SCREAMING )
( MUSIC PLAYING )
Subtitles by explosiveskull Colored by novabros